

Gareth Graveline-Pleau

Freelance Web Developer

Barrie, Ontario705-500-0181

Profile

Enthusiastic junior full stack web developer with 1+ year of experience creating dynamic and responsive MERN based web applications, with a focus on accessibility, minimalism and environmentally conscious programming and design. Eagerly learning and applying best practices with vanilla JS, MySQL, Node, React, GCP and associated technologies.

Education

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development

September 2020 - August 2021

York University

Certificate in HTML/CSS and Javascript with jQuery

March 2021

TestDome

Certificate in Pre-University Calculus

April 2020

Delft University

Bachelor of Arts in Political Science

September 2007 - August 2012

University of Guelph Dean's List

Work experience

Freelance Web Developer

August 2021 - Current

Independent

Creating clean, dynamic, minimalist, accessible MERN stack based websites for clients.

Web Development Intern

July 2021 - August2021

3rdi Lab Inc.

Building a front end web application with extensive use of the augmented reality javascript framework AR.js.

Clerk November 2017 - Current

Loblaws Inc.

Receiving and unloading shipments.

Skills

MySQL

One year of experience in this popular relational database system as a part of MERN stack based web applications

Node

One year of experience creating projects with Node and extensive use of NPM packages such as Express, esm, bcrypt, dotenv, axios, jsonwebtoken and reactstrap

React

One year of experience in this popular JS library creating dynamic, component-based, user-friendly web apps

One year of experience with vanilla JS and ES6 best practices creating functional REST APIs

AR.js

Six months of experience with the AR.js javascript library which helps introduce exciting, augmented reality components to any web app

Created with 📅 VisualCV